Subtitle created by - Aorion -
中文字幕翻译 by 杨小溪
"The Accountant (2016)" ^ (Run time 02:07:54)
搞什么？
What the fuck?
等等，我要打电话叫人！
Wait, I gonna call them in!
退后！
Move back!
为什么要这样做？
Why are you doing this?
去死吧，混蛋！
Take that, motherfucker!
拜托
Please.
请停手吧！
Just fucking stop it!
把枪放下
Put your gun down!
我求你了
Come on.
求你了
Please.
我向你求饶了 我没有动过他
I'm fucking begging you. I didn't touch him.
我没动过那个老头
I didn't touch that old man.
我根本……
I wasn't even...
会计刺客
the accountant
星期天入土 这就是所罗门·格兰迪的一生
Buried on Sunday. That was the end Of Solomon Grundy.
所罗门·格兰迪
Solomon Grundy.
不要乱动 Justine
Justine, please.
这叫“刺激行为” 是一种自我刺激
It's called “stimming.” It's self-stimulation
就好像我和你 会敲手指、磨牙
Where as, you and I might tap our fingers, grind our teeth,
或者咬指甲 你儿子变成了前后摇而已
bite our nails. Your son rocks back and forth.
虽然更明显 但绝对是正常行为
It's more obvious, but perfectly natural.
我们来这里 因为我们听说你是这方面的专家
We came here, because we heard you specialized in, in...
什么来着？我们得的病叫？
What is it? What does he have?
我不喜欢给这种状态取名字
Mm, not a fan of labels, ma'am.
你儿子是一位优秀的年轻人
Your son is a remarkable young man.
却在我用吸尘器的时候会发狂
Who goes crazy when you turn the vacuum on.
永远只穿一件T恤 不让你抱他
Wears one Tee-shirt. Won't let you hug him.
噪音、强光 对你儿子这样的人来说
Loud noises, bright lights can be especially difficult
是比较不能接受的
for someone like your son.
T恤的话 很可能是对那种布料有依赖
The shirt, most likely fabric sensitivity.
拥抱、亲密行为、接触 确实可能是个挑战
Hugging, closeness, touching,
that can be a challenge, yes.
如果是别人的孩子 那就是挑战
When it's somebody else's child, it's a challenge.
当是你自己的孩子时 那就是问题
When it's yours, it's a problem.
我的工作主要关注的是教育
My practice focuses on education.
我乐意用你儿子的节奏和他待在一起
I like to work with your son at his speed.
帮他发展一些他日后需要用来生活的技能
Help him develop the skills he'll need to live a full life.
让他学会交流、眼神接触和理解人们的非语言指示
Communicating, eye contact,
understanding non-verbal cues;
还有交上朋友
making friends.
他唯一的朋友是他弟弟
The only friend he has is his little brother.
我相信只是搬来搬去并没有什么帮助
I'm sure moving from base to base doesn't help it.
我丈夫是军人 也就是说我们都是
My husband's in the Army, which means we all are.
你愿意让你儿子这个暑假和我们待在一起吗？
Would you be willing to let your son stay with us for the summer.
免费的，只是和我一起待在这个友好的环境里
Free of charge, working with me
in a sensory-friendly environment.
不可能的事
That's not gonna happen.
如果他受不了噪音和强光 那他就更需要去适应
If loud noises and bright lights bother him, he needs more of it,
而不是逃避
not less.
真实世界可不是那么友好！
The world is not a sensory-friendly place
那才是他该学习如何生存的地方
and that's where he needs to learn where to live.
不是这里
Not in here.
博士 依你所见
Doctor, in your opinion.
我们儿子能过上正常人的生活吗？
Can our son lead a normal life?
要看什么叫正常了
Define normal.
我得完成 我得完成
I need to finish. I need to finish.
所罗门·格兰迪 星期一落地
Solomon Grundy, born on a Monday,
星期二受洗 星期三结婚
Christened on Tuesday, Married on Wednesday,
星期四染疾 星期五病重
Took ill on Thursday, Grew worse on Friday,
星期六去世 星期天入土
Died on Saturday, Buried on Sunday.
我要做完！
I need to finish.
所罗门·格兰迪 星期一落地
Solomon Grundy, born on a Monday,
星期二受洗 星期三结婚
Christened on Tuesday, Married on Wednesday,
星期四染疾 星期五病重
Took ill on Thursday, Grew worse on Friday,
星期六去世
Died on Saturday...
星期天入土
Buried on Sunday.
我…
I...
我从没想过自己会放弃
I never thought of myself as a quitter.
我们祖传四代都是农民
You know…4th generation farmer.
但是 在房产税
But, between...the property taxes and
灌溉设施花销、保险费的夹击下
fertilizer cost, insurance.
我就破产了
Ah, the hell with it.
要打断你一下提醒你
Well...just temporarily remind you,
今年我们的税还是用信用卡交的
we put this year's taxes on our credit card
你喜欢这个吗？我自己做的
Do you like it? I made it myself.
不 并不是特别喜欢
No, not particularly.
但你卖出去过吗？
but…you ever sell one?
在教堂集市上卖出去过
At church fairs now and again.
所以Rice先生 你经营着国税局可能认为是“家庭作坊”的产业
Mrs Rice, you may have what the IRS
calls a “a home-based business.”
你在家里什么地方做这些项链？
What room do you use in your house when you made those?
没有固定的地方 就看我当时在哪
I don't, really.Just wherever I happen to be, I guess,
可能在电视前 可能在厨房桌子上
in front of the TV, at the kitchen table...
可能会把珠子洒得满饭厅都是 但是Frank不…
I'll spread my beads out in the dining room
but Frank...
好 但如果你能努力想一下
Yes, it would be better if you could try to remember
有什么固定的地方会更好
the one specific space that you use.
你们家占地29013平方米
Your home is 29,013 square meter.
国税局法令准许我们从你工作室占住房的比例
IRS code allows us to deduct from your taxable income
来扣除相应的税收比例
a percentage of your work space relative to your overall home...
-什么？ -Rice先生
- What? - Mr Rice.
Rice夫人的工作室、你家的饭厅有多大？
How big is your dining room, Mrs Rice's office?
我不会把那叫做我的工作室…
I wouldn't so much as call it an office...
大概…有两百
It's...approximately 200 uh...
-那就三百平方米吧 -很好
- Make it 300 square feet. - Excellent.
-Rice夫人 -Dolores
- Mrs Rice. - Dolores.
Dolores 你买材料的时候 会上网买吗？
Dolores, when you order supplies, do you order online?
不会 我只会去珠子店里买
I don't, I just upon over to the beads store.
怎么去？
Example?
我开车去 我们有卡车
I drive, the truck.
公司货车
The company truck.
进来
Come in.
King先生 你现在已经远远地越过你的合法权限范围了
Mr. King, you've wandered so far outside your legal purview.
作为南方信托银行的总裁 我想保护我客户的隐私
As the president of Southern Trust Bank, I intend to protect my customer's privacy...
别说了 你作为一家银行的总裁
Stop talking. You have a very cavalier attitude for the president of a bank
为了保护那些混蛋就态度如此傲慢
for such a piss poor capital cushion.
现在 我想要你们银行过去两年每一笔转账
Now, I want a record of every transaction abayed has for the last two years;
存款、取款、柜台支票和信用卡的全部记录
deposits, withdrawals, cashier checks, credit cards.
不管是伯明翰还是巴林的客户 这是财政部命令
Birmingham or Bahrain, it is now Treasury business.
拜拜
Good bye.
Medina.
-我发音发对了吗？ -对的，Medina
- Am I saying that correctly? - Uh, Medina, yes sir.
我读过你所有负责的案件档案，King主任
I've read all your case files, Director King.
都非常厉害
It's impressive work. Very.
Marybeth Ascension Medina.
巴蒂摩尔大学优等毕业生 刑事司法学位
Graduated University of Baltimore cum laude with a degree in criminal justice.
在巴蒂摩尔警察局当分析员两年
2 years Baltimore PD as an analyst.
国安局当分析员两年
2 more at Homeland, analyst again.
过去五年都在我们财政局
And the last 5 years here at Treasury.
还是分析员
Analyst.
上个月在Lorenz调查员的案子里你做出了巨大贡献
You did the heavy lifting on Agent Lorenz's case last month.
是 我帮助了她 不过是Lorenz调查员她
I worked on it, yeah,but Agent Lorenz...
为什么你没有申请晋升为调查员？
Why haven't you applied for promotion to agent?
你已经在做他们的工作了
You've already doing the work.
分析员挺适合我的
Analyst is a good fit.
我也喜欢这个职位
And I enjoy the work.
所以…
So...
你是个骗子 Medina
Well, you're a liar, Medina.
11到18岁 你都在马里兰州的监狱的青少年看守所里
Ward to the State of Maryland's foster care and
Juvenile Detention System from age 11 to 18.
被控持有武器 殴打伤人
Weapons chargers,  assault and battery.
哇 还有企图谋杀
Ouch, attempted murder.
那些记录是封锁了的
Those records are sealed.
这把枪是0.9吗？
Is that a 9mm? (Tattoo)
是0.45
.45
你最好还是坐回来 年轻人
You better sit your ass back down in that chair, young lady.
这是你人生的重要时刻
This is a big moment for you.
不要冲动 做个好选择
Make a good choice.
在政府工作申请时撒谎可是重罪
Lying on a federal employment application is a felony.
所以现在
So, right now,
站在现在的你和坐牢的你之间的 只有我
I'm the only thing standing between you and significant prison time.
你要干什么？
What do you want?
你喜欢猜谜吗 Marybeth Medina？
Do you like puzzles, Marybeth Medina?
我说话算话 孩子 欢迎你随时来我们家
I meant what I said, son, you're welcome out to the place anytime.
你钓鱼吗？我们有个两公顷大的鱼塘 里面全是鲢鱼和鲈鱼
Do you fish? I got a two-acre pond that is just thick with catfish and bass.
我不钓鱼 我玩射击
I don't fish. I shoot.
太好了 我们农场也很适合玩射击
Oh well, the farm's a perfect place to do a little plinking. So...
好吧 谢谢你
Well, thank you.
保重 孩子
You take care, son.
谢谢
Thank you.
我女儿要过来找我吃午饭 我觉得你俩可能合得来
My daughter is meeting me for lunch. I think you two just might hit it off.
见到你很高兴
Nice to see you.
照片已经调清晰了
Already enhanced.
三年前一个国际特工在安特卫普拍下的
It was taken 3 years ago in Antwerp by an undercover Interpol agent.
目标人物是右边那个
Their target's on the far right.
对 Zalmay Atta
Yeah, Zalmay Atta.
继续说
Go on.
世界最大的鸦片运输生意的老大
Run the world's largest opium pipe line.
和卡尔扎伊、塔利班都有关系
Ties to Karzai, Ghani,Taliban.
反正他本该是无法接近的
I mean he was considered untouchable.
看看其他照片 告诉我你看到了什么
Look at the rest. Tell me what you see
大多数人我都知道 他们都是大人物
I remember most of the rests…they were huge.
集中精力 他们不全都是那些人
Focus. They're all not arrest.
有同一个男人
It's the same man.
Lou Carrol.
不论真假 这是个化名
For what it's worth. It's an alias.
这是香港照片五年前拍到的
The Hong Kong photo was backed about 5 years.
这张照片里 他叫Carl Gauss
And that one, he's Carl Gauss.
东京 特拉维夫 尼泊尔 还有人看到他在德黑兰
Tokyo, Tel Aviv, Nepal, there was a sighting in Tehran.
这些大佬都把这个人叫做
All describing the same man:
会计 我们的会计 会计师
“an accountant,” “our accountant,” “the accountant.”
会计师 CPA会计师那种？
“The Accountant”? Like, “CPA accountant”?
好了
Okay.
假如你是贩毒集团的老大
Say you're the headof the Sinaloa Cartel.
每天集团收入的钱得用大卡车来装
Now, the cartel count their money by weighing it in eighteen wheelers.
但突然阳光晴朗的一天 你的内部洗钱手
But one sunny Mexican day, your in-house money-scrubber
过来告诉你你们少了三千万美元
comes to you and says you're thirty million light.
你可以信任谁来帮你做这个财务调查 来找你被偷掉的钱？
Who can you trust to do the forensic accounting, track your stolen cash?
德勤事务所吗？还是H&R？
Deloitte and Touche? H&R Block?
你不得不找那种私人专家 来打开你多年来冷冰冰的账簿
You somehow, contact an individual capable of coming in cold, un-cooking years of books...
然后把问题找出来
and getting out alive.
七个月后我就退休了
I retire in seven months.
退休之前 我得知道这个人是谁
Before I do, I need to know who he is.
他做了什么
How he does it.
你想 谁能从这些大佬手中活下来？
I mean, who survives this kind of clientele?
毕竟他们有那么多不想别人知道的秘密
The secrets this guys has.
你到底想让我做什么？
What exactly do you want me to do?
直接向我汇报
Report directly to me.
别再管其他的案子
No other case work.
不能有财务部其他任务人参与进来
No other Treasury personnel involve.
到这个月底 只会有两种可能发生
By the end of the month, one of 2 things would have occurred.
解开这个案子
Resolution of this case,
或者我们更新你的资料
or we update your photo.
ZOLOFT 100 mg
妈妈！
Mom! Mom! Mom!
你要去哪？！
Where are you going?
妈妈！
Mom!Mom!
你根本不关心
You just don't care.
你总是在控制他！
You always control him!
妈妈！不要走！
Mom!No!
不要！别走！
No!No!
妈妈！
Mom!Mom!
妈妈！你要去哪？
Mom!Where are you going?
-我们本来有帮助的！-那就留下来
- We had help! - Then stay.
-你拒绝了帮助！ -留在这 哪都别去
- You threw it away! - Stay here, don't go anywhere!
-妈妈！ -喂
- Mom! - Hey.
喂！喂！
Hey. Hey.
就这样
That's it.
没事的 慢慢来
There we go. There we go.
所罗门·格兰迪
Solomon Grundy,
-星期一落地 -所罗门·格兰迪
- Born on Monday.- Solomon Grundy.
-好了吗？-星期一落地
- Alright? - Born on a Monday,
星期二受洗
Christened on Tuesday,
-就这样 -星期三结婚
-There we go. - Married on Wednesday,
星期四染疾
Took ill on Thursday,
星期五病重 星期六去世
Worse on Friday, Died on Saturday,
星期天入土
Buried on Sunday.
这就是所罗门·格兰迪的一生
That was the end Of Solomon Grundy.
再来一遍
Do it again.
所罗门·格兰迪 星期一落地
Solomon Grundy, born on Monday,
看来某些人看太多西部片了
Looks like somebody's seen too many westerns.
嗯 他肯定是
Yeah, he must be what...
一公里远？
a mile out?
就算我见过最厉害的也…
Not on my best day...
真是神了！
Holy shit.
好 听我说
Okay, listen to me.
音…调…变化 好吗？
In... flec... tion, alright?
听好了 听我的音调
Listen, just listen to my tone.
跟我说 “噢！你又大了一岁了！
I say,"Oh, you look another year older."
我不知道我以后能不能离开这鬼地方”
"I don't know if I would ever going to get out of this fucking place."
你说一遍
And you say.
你可能是对的 Francis 你已经非常老了可能没办法活着…
You're probably right, Francis. You're extremely old most unlikely to survive your...
不对 等等 不是要你说这个
No, hold on. That's not what you say.
我们两年来每晚都住在一起
2 years together every night, you know.
我可以用黑钱帮你买博士学位 但你得学会这些
I give you PhD in black money, but you got to learn this.
-这很重要 -你很受挫
- This is crucial. - You're frustrated.
-我怎么了？ -你很受挫
- What am I? - You're frustrated.
对 正是如此 我很受挫
That's what I am. I'm frustrated.
好 好 非常好
Good, good. Excellent.
终于对了 来 我们再来练下一个
Finally. Alright, let's do another one.
熄灯啦 小姐们
Lights out, ladies.
熄灯
Lights out.
姓名和地址 开始
Names and addresses, go.
Cenyon Ivankov 奥德赛Primorsky大街79号
Cenyon Ivankov, 79 Primorsky Boulevard, Odessa.
Meier兄弟 Moushein and Tzak 耶路撒冷舍伍德大道221号
The Meier brothers, Moushein and Tzak, 221 Sherwood Avenue, Jerusalem.
Dominick Rabito 布鲁克林法院街96号
Dominick Rabito, 96 Court Street, Brooklyn.
去找Bobby问
Ask for Bobby.
你知道我老了 我可能记得的东西
You know, I'm old, I may be remembering things
比以前美好了些
a little rosier than they were.
你要填好报税表和那些分项扣税额
I mean if you want to fill out 1040s and itemized deductions,
每年省出五万块 这是个生意 但你一旦走了这条路 这路就…
pulling 50 grand a year, I mean it's a living, because if you go down this road, this road...
你就不能回头了 你懂吗？很危险 你懂吗？
You can't go back, you understand? It's dangerous, do you understand?
我懂
I understand.
你找一个你能信任的人 只需要一个
You find one person you can trust, just one.
不要犯我的错误 你得拍拍屁股走人
And do not make my mistake, you keep moving your ass around.
他们今天给我了新的接班人选
They gave me a new handler today.
我不喜欢他 他好蠢
I don't like this guy. He's dull.
你很担心
Worried.
对 去他的
Yeah, fuck it.
晚安 孩子
Good night, son.
晚安 Francis
Good night, Francis.
苏黎世怎么样？或者沙特？
What about Zurich? Or Saudi Arabia?
瑞士很便宜
The Swiss are cheap.
迪拜是个选择 但我们在那太显眼了
Dubai is one thing but we're too conspicuous in the Kingdom.
-我投芝加哥 -为什么？
- I vote Chicago. - Why?
网络论坛里有消息更新 人们在找你
There's an update in online chatter, people looking for you.
-什么人？ -不太友好的人
- What people? - The unfriendly kind.
我们这次找个合法的客户吧
Let's try a legitimate client for once.
不要再为垄断集团、军火商、洗钱人和刺客工作了
No cartels, arms brokers, money launderers, assassins.
我喜欢安全 喜欢你安全
I like safe. I like you safe.
每个人都有藏着的东西 至少贼盗有信用
Everyone's hiding something. At least there's honor among thieves.
伊州的电子制造商也有信用
There is honor among Illinois electronic manufacturers.
他们就在你后院 你都不用动身去别的地方
They're in your current backyard, no risk of movement.
你会见见他们吗？
You'll meet?
好 我见见吧
Yeah, I'll meet.
还有最后一件事
One last piece of business.
只卖雷诺阿那幅
Just the Renoir.
我这没有买家要买雷诺阿
I don't have a buyer for the Renoir.
波洛克那幅画也可以动的 你难道永远留着它吗？
The Pollock can move. Will you ever let it go?
你在吗？
Hello?
只卖雷诺阿 开价调低些
Just the Renoir. Drop the price.
一声叹息
Heavy sigh.
去工作吧 梦中人
Go to work, Dreamboat.
Wolff先生 我有点怀疑我们在浪费你的时间
Uh, Mr. Wolff, I half suspect we're wasting your time.
我很确定你们没有
I'm quite sure you're not.
你怎么知道？
And you know this how?
我在算时间
I'm on the clock.
好吧 靠 那我希望我们没有在浪费我们的时间
Well, shit, I hope we're not wasting ours then...
好吧 开个玩笑 我觉得如果你要看账簿 就是要翻山越岭
Look, kidding aside, I think if you saw our books, you'd run for the hills.
我们的会计系统相当复杂
We have an incredibly complicated accounting system,
有数百件不同项目的折旧细则
depreciation schedules on hundreds of different items,
全职和合同员工 国防部批准的账目
full time and contract employees, Department of Defense classified accounts.
简直是一堆天文数字
It's a numerical shitstorm.
我需要看过去十年来的所有账簿
I'll need to see all those books for the past 10 years,
银行对账单 还有所有客户和供应商的清单
bank statements, a complete list of clients and vendors,
都打印出来 只能给我看 所有信息都在这里
hard copies printed out, my eyes only. All the information is right here.
好吧 好吧 你看
Okay, whoa, whoa. Look.
这件事上周才引起我的注意
This all came to my attention only last week..
是有个新人会计注意到了这个异常
Now, a junior cost accountant stuck her nose where it didn't belong
显然她也不知道这个异常到底是什么
and obviously had no idea what she was looking at.
是Lamar先生反应过激 根本没有钱不见！
Lamar's overreacting, there is no missing money!
先生 你做这间公司的首席财政官做了多久？
How long have you been CFO of this company, sir?
十五年
15 years.
那请给我过去十五年的所有账簿 谢谢
I need the books for the past fifteen, please.
你真是太唐突了！
Well, you're goddamn blunt.
我是Lamar Blackburn最久的朋友
I'm Lamar Blackburn's oldest friend.
当他发明RC机器人被Shack电台称作垃圾时 我就在他身边
I've been by his side since he was turnin' out RC robots that Radio Shack called crap.
他不说话的话 我不可能拿公司一分钱
I wouldn't take a dime without his say so.
-你生气了 -噢 真是屁话
- You're angry. - Oh, this is bullshit.
Wolff先生 和你打交道真是不寻常啊
Unusual way of making contact with you, Mr. Wolff.
是Mansoor Lakhani推荐你过来的
You were recommended by Mansoor Lakhani.
我们为他的女儿定做了义肢
We custom made prosthetics for this man's daughter.
你可能知道她在一场汽车爆炸中失去了双腿
You may know that she lost both legs to a car bomb
爆炸就发生在Lakhani在拉合尔的工厂外
outside his investment firm in Lahore.
他告诉我哥哥Lamar 你是一个不可思议的人
He told my brother, Lamar, that you were nothing short of supernatural.
Lakhani先生拥有剑桥和加州理工学院两所名校的数学高等学位
Mr Lakhani holds advance degrees in mathematics from Cambridge and Caltech.
这样一个天才 为何还需要你？
Why does a man like that need you?
我不会讨论客户的事情
I don't discuss client business.
Carl Gauss 五年前在香港
Carl Gauss -5 years ago Hong Kong
CARL FRIEDRICH GAUSS
数学王子 The Prince of Mathematicians
Lou Carroll -
Colombia , Tehran,  Tel Aviv
Louis Carroll
你觉得那位年轻人现在在想什么？
What do you suppose that young man is thinking right now?
我的手臂怎么还有感觉？
Why do I still feel my arm?
所有事情怎么能如此糟糕？来得如此快？
How did everything go so wrong so fast?
好冷啊 把暖气打开
It's cold. Turn up the heat.
Christian Wolff 对吧？
Christian Wolff, I presume.
Blackburn先生
Mr. Blackburn.
Lamar.
跟我来
Come with me.
你了解Living Robotics三个收入源吗？
Are you aware of Living Robotics' three income streams?
消费型电子产品 新一代义肢 无人操作的军用设备
Consumer electronics, next generation prosthetics, unmanned military applications.
义肢这一项在过去十年展现出了非凡的增长速度
Prosthetics division showed tremendous growth over the last 10 years,
现在看起来已经成熟了
it's seems to have matured.
消费产品则是你最高的收入来源
Consumer product is your highest source of revenue.
第二高的则是国防部合约 义肢项目在第三位
followed closely by Defense department contracts, prosthetics sits on three.
你掌握得很齐全
You are well informed.
我没结过婚 也没有孩子
I never married. Never had kids.
这家公司就是我的孩子
This company is my child.
就是这样 赚钱从来不是我的目标
That's it, money has never been a motivation.
资产负债表 收支报表
Balance sheets, profit and loss statements.
我的大脑和你的运作方式不一样
My mind doesn't function the way your's works.
我需要你帮我顾头顾尾
I need you to be my eyes and ears, Chris.
需要什么的话 尽管告诉我
Whatever you need to do your job, you let me know.
我明早开始工作
I'll start in the morning.
苏黎世 瑞士
Zurich, Switzerland.
婊子养的
Son of a bitch.
不好意思？
Excuse me?
你他妈以为你是谁？
Who the fuck do you think you are?
你他妈知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who the fuck I am?
Simon Dewey.
杜威资本的创始人和CEO
The founder, CEO of Dewey Capital.
美国人 大人物
American. Shocking.
我买了绑架保险 这一点你显然知道
I have kidnap insurance, you obviously know that.
抱歉 但我怎么知道你买了…
Sorry, but how would I know that you have...
你们这些人真是很厉害
You people are fucking amazing...
你知道吗 当你这样打断一个人说话时
You know, when you interrupt somebody like that,
你会让人觉得你对他们说的东西不感兴趣
it makes them feel that you're just not interested in what they have to say.
或者是觉得你们说的东西
Or maybe you just think what you have to say
比我们说的东西更重要
is more important than what I have to say.
你是这样想的吗？
Is that what you think?
有把枪 你就觉得你很厉害了 是吗？
That gun, makes you a big man, does it?
枪？
This gun?
不是吧
Come on.
我是一支小型私人安全部队的一员
I'm part of a small potent department of a private security force.
我们有个客户 叫做欧洲制造企业
We have a client, it's called a...European manufacturing concern.
你们在一起削弱他们的股票
You're shortening their stocks simultaneously,
散步假消息说这家公司有问题
spreading false rumors regarding the harm of the company.
造成股价下跌后 你赚了几百万 但是
The result in declining stock price has made you your millions, but...
那都是我的客户付的钱
It's been on my client's expense.
他们不得不裁掉了几百人 Simon
They have been forced to cut hundreds of jobs, Simon.
被裁掉的都是代代做那行的金属工人 有家室的
These are third generation metal workers, people with families.
而抚恤金也因为你都变得没有价值
Pensions are being rendered worthless because of you.
所以 你现在会停手了 对吧？
But, you'll stop now, correct?
什么公司？
Which company?
答案错误 Simon
Wrong answer, Simon.
看吧
Look..
嗷！
Ow.
我打得同一个地方 Simon
It's the same spot, Simon.
为什么你要惹我去打你同一个地方呢？
Why'd you let me hit you in the same exact spot?
我只是想问
I only meant.
因为我们为好几十家公司服务
We all chose positions on dozens of companies.
我靠 SImon
Shit, Simon.
你的意思是你不止给一家公司
I suppose, you spreading false information
散布了假消息 你在做这个对吗？
about more than one company, if that's what you're doing?
那你现在应该全部停手
You just gonna have to stop shortening them all.
太荒谬了 我不可能…
That's ridiculous. I can't be expected...
对 抬高你的下巴 Simon 不要把血溅到我的手表上了
Alright, keep your chin up, son. No pouting on my watch.
你已经长大了 你只是
Yeah, you're a man, You're just...
以你自己的方式长大了
You're a man in your own way.
好了 Simon
Alright, Simon.
我是财经杂志的忠实读者
I'm an avid reader of the Journal.
我希望可以在杂志上看到我们的合作
So I expect cooperation be reflected there.
Simon 同意了吗？
Simon, are we good?
怎么样？
Yeah?
好孩子 Simon 我为你骄傲
Good boy, Simon. I'm proud of you.
噢 你好
Oh, hello.
早上好
Good morning.
噢 嗨
Oh. Hi.
-嗯… -嗨
- Um... - Hi.
我是Dana Cummings 你就是…那个顾问 Wolff先生？
I'm Dana Cummings. You're... the consultant, Mr. Wolff?
-Chris -嗨 Chirs 那么 嗯
- Chris.- Hi, Chris... then. Um...
我是Dana
I'm Dana.
Cummings.
对 嗯…
Yes. Um...
这些是所有你要求的资料 我交叉整理了一下
These are all the files you wanted. I cross-reference them
按照年份和字母表顺序 那么…
by year and alphabetical. So...
肯定花了你一晚上吧
It must have taken you all night.
当然花了
It sure did.
好 那么…
Right. So...
那么…
So.
你想说什么 Dana Cummings?
What do you want, Dana Cummings?
噢 是Blackburn先生 嗯…
Oh, Mr. Blackburn, um...
不好意思 是他说我应该
Sorry, he said I should...
毕竟我是第一个发现不见
I'm the person who first noticed the missing
-我觉得不见的是钱 -好 我明白 我会找到的
- what I think was the missing money.- Yes, I understand. I'll find it.
对 我以为我们可以…一起吃个午餐什么的
Yeah, I thought we could...have lunch and...
我带了午餐
I brought my lunch.
不是 我也自己带了午餐
No, I bring my own lunch too.
我可以回答你的任何问题
I can answer any questions that you have.
我没有问题
I have no questions.
喔 好吧 看来你是想…
Yeah, okay. Yeah, you want to...
- 自己工作 -是的 谢谢你
- make your own assessment. - Yes, thank you.
好吧
Okay.
嗯…
Um...
要找我的话 我在财务部
I'm in accounting if you need anything.
那儿有一些给你准备的甜甜圈
There is a... some donuts there for you.
我不吃甜甜圈
I don't eat donuts.
好吧
Okay.
国务卿先生
Mr. Secretary.
先生 现在有人质疑你把南佛罗里达州的银行
Sir, there's been speculation that your ability to link banks in South Florida
和恐怖分子洗钱的事情联系在一起 实际上是告密者的功劳
to money laundering efforts of terrorists are actually the result of a whistle-blower?
或者国家安全局的功劳 你能评论下吗？
Or the NSA? You care to comment?
让我把这个问题交给我们工作小组的组长
Let me turn this over to the head of my task force
金融犯罪主任 Raymond King
Financial Crimes Director, Raymond King.
大家好
Folks.
这里面没什么秘密
There's no great mystery here.
也没什么精彩的 只是靠团队合作
Nothing fancy. Just team effort,
靠大家长时间的传统调查工作
comprised of long hours of good old-fashioned investigative work.
还有问题吗？
Question?
拜托 Sorkis 给我点有用的
Please, Sorkis, give me something.
我把照片里的人脸和纽约警察局资料库的监视器资料匹配了下
I match the face of the man in the photo to a surveillance video in the NYPD data base.
等等…纽约警察局？
Wait wait wait... NYPD?
你发现了什么？
What did you find?
06年时 这个男人用一把牛排刀杀了两名暴徒
2006, your guy takes out 2 mob enforcers with a steak knife
他从一家意大利餐厅走到街上
he lifted off from an Italian restaurant down the street.
然后进了杀手们的贼窝 一连杀了七个人
Then he strolls into a den of stone cold killers and goes on a 7 man killing spree.
用的是那些杀手的武器
Using their own weapons.
爆头 爆头 全是爆头
Head shot, head shot, head shot.
Sorkis 停一下
Sorkis, stop.
那个贼窝 在哪里？
The den of stone cold killers, where is this?
Ravenite 那里是甘比诺家族的总部
Ravenite, headquarters of the Gambino crime family.
他杀了绰号为“小托尼”的Anthony
He killed Anthony, "Little Tony" Bazzano.
鉴证科认为死因是重击
Forensics list cause of death as blunt force trauma.
那个男人一次就踢爆了他的头
Your boy kicked him in the head, once.
再来一次 再来
Again, play it again.
喂 喂
Hey, hey, hey.
我最好还是叫人来！
I better call it in!
我这里还有段音频
I also got an audio file here.
是警方在Ravenite窃听录下的
Inside of the Ravenite, it was bugged.
我求你了
Come on.
求你了
Please.
那是小托尼的声音
That's Little Tony.
我向你求饶 我没有动过他
I'm fucking begging. I didn't touch him.
我没动过那个老头！
I didn't touch that old man!
好了 以最快速度把这录音发给我
Okay, give me the recording ASAP.
我根本…
I wasn't even...
MB 你是财务部的分析员
MB, you're an analyst for Treasury.
你被卷进了什么破事里？
What the hell have you got yourself into?
你要打什么让膳魔师凹成这样？
What do you have to hit to dent a steel thermos?
只是很老了
It's just old.
你是怎么…进入财经顾问这一行的？
How did you, um... get into financial consulting?
劳动局的数据显示这一行发展最快
Department of Labor statistics indicate it's one of the fastest growing professions.
精算学也发展迅猛
Actuarial sciences are experiencing a tremendous growth as well.
好吧
Okay.
我喜欢数字的平衡
I like the balance of it.
就好像找问题 不那么明显的缺点
You know, like finding things that aren't obvious.
而且我父亲也是个会计
Plus my dad was an accountant.
实际上
He actually...
他很懂这一套
You know, he had the whole schtick.
他…
He..
你知道 他用那些小的记账本 绿色封皮那种
You know, the little amortization book, with the green eye-shade.
还有过时的口袋护套和…
The, like dorky pocket protector and...
我也用口袋护套
I've got a pocket protector.
你这个挺好的 我是说他的过时了
That's a nice one. I mean, his was dorky, I guess.
你的挺好的
Yours is nice.
总之 他让我走进了这一行
Yeah, but he convinced me to go into the field.
因为我开始是想学艺术的 在芝加哥艺术学院 但是
Because I wanted to study art. At the Art Institute of Chicago. But...
学艺术就付不起房贷
Art doesn't pay the mortgage.
“艺术是供不了房的 年轻人”
"Art doesn't pay the mortgage, young lady."
我爸的品味最多就是喜欢《狗狗玩扑克》这幅画了
Dad's tastes ran more to Dogs Playing Poker.
我喜欢《狗狗打扑克》那幅画
I like Dogs Playing Poker.
因为狗本身不会参与赌博 所以显得很不协调
Because dogs would never bet on things. So it's incongruous.
我喜欢不协调
I like incongruity.
对 《狗狗打扑克》挺好的
Yeah, Dogs Playing Poker is nice.
只是有点…不同罢了
It's just sort of... just different.
所以我之后开始在芝加哥大学念会计 “在那根本了无生趣”
So I studied accounting at the University of Chicago. “Where fun goes to die.”
为什么？
Why?
什么为什么？
Why what?
为什么芝加哥大学了无生趣？
Why does fun go to die at the University of Chicago?
没 只是一种说法而已
Oh, no. It's just an expression.
我开玩笑呢
I'm joking.
对哦
Right.
-我还是让你静会吧 -好
- I'll leave you to it. - Okay.
你在这里需要什么 记得来找我
Let me know if you need anything while you're here.
-祝你有愉快的一天！-你也是！
- Have a nice day! - Yes, you too.
我向你求饶了 我没有动过他
I'm fucking begging. I didn't touch him.
我没有动过那个老头
I didn't touch that old man.
我根本…
I wasn't even...
好了
Okay..
来点有用的
Give me something.
我…
I..
我向你求饶了 我没有动过他
I'm fucking begging. I didn't touch him.
我没有动过那个老头 我根本…
I didn't touch that old man. I wasn't even...
底层音轨分离 Subfloor Vocal Track Isolated
所罗门·格兰迪 星期一落地
Solomon Grundy, born on a Monday,
星期二受洗
Christened on Tuesday,
星期一落地 星期二受洗
Born on a Monday, Christened on Tuesday,
星期三结婚
Married on Wednesday,
进来 快进来
Come in. Come in. Come in.
你得看看 看这个
You have to see this. Look at this.
会吓死你的
It's going to blow you away.
我是说 它自己跳了出来
I mean, it'll just... jump right out at you.
-就在这 -嗯嗯
- There it is. - Uh-huh.
这是Living Robotics十年前交税前的收入
Living Robotics, 10 years ago, earnings before interest, tax, depreciation,
$14,495,719.
再看九年前交税前的收入
9 years ago. earning before tax depreciation.
总收入增加 利润却下降了
Revenues go up, profits go down.
没有大型支出拉低这个利润
No large capital expenditures dragging profits down.
原材料和劳务支出也没有大涨
No spike in raw materials or labor costs.
八年前 利润和总收入都涨了
Year 8, profits and revenue both go up,
但是不是按比例涨的 X不再对得上Y
but not at a comparable fashion. X no longer equals Y.
6年 5年 4年 3年前…
6, 5, 4, 3.
公司在赚钱 但却有漏洞
You're making money but there's a leak.
漏洞在于
The leak is...
漏洞 东西放哪了
The leak. Where's the leak?
SLEWITT制造单 这些是我签的单子
SLEWITT manufacturing.I signed these checks.
-谁授权你签的？ -Ed…Chilton先生
- Who authorized it? - Ed... Mr. Chilton.
这个是为消费领域做电子组件
They make electronic assemblies for the consumer division.
不是 错了 看看这个
No, they don't. Look at this.
你发现了什么吗？
You notice anything?
-每个金额的第二位数字都是3  -对
- Second number in each is a 3. - Yeah.
大多数人在写一堆假金额时会不自觉地使用固定的数字…
Most people, when generating random numbers tends to relies subconsciously on certain...
-一种规律 -规律 对
- ... patterns. - Patterns. Yeah.
对！
Yes.
-我想对了！ -你是对的
- I was right. - You were right.
-耶 -我…
- Yeah. - Uh, I'm...
我已经花了几个月来研究这些账目 才总结完一个财政年
I went through these ledgers for months. And I got through one fiscal year.
你一个晚上就做完了十五个财政年！
You went through 15. Overnight.
这还不是最厉害的 看 最厉害的是…
It's not even the best part, look. This part is...
他们把大量钱漏给一个不存在的公司
They're routing money to a company that doesn't exist.
我们的利润还在上涨 而且持续上涨
And yet profits go up, and they continue going up.
完全不合理
It absolutely makes no sense.
-这些钱从哪漏来的？ -这些钱从哪漏来的？这才是关键！
- Where's the money coming from? - Where's the money coming from? Exactly!
-不是投资吗？ -投资我查过了
- It's not inventory? - Inventory checked out.
-给供应商的退款？ -不是 那个没问题
- Chargebacks to vendors?- No, perfectly in order.
内部收支抵消？
Internal offsets?
不是 你想错了
No, that's a terrible idea.
嗯
Um.
Cummings.
你应该在做我付钱请你做的工作
You're needed in whatever area I'm paying you to be needed in.
对不起
Sorry.
所以？
And?
300万 345万…600万 697万…1200万…
3 million, three hundred forty five...6 million, three hundred ninety seven...12 million...
6100万 6亿1790万……一共是6亿1679万…
Sixty one million, six hundred and seventy nine thousand...
$ 61,679,000 ...
还有些零头
and some change.
谁做的？谁最有可能？
Who did it? Best guess?
我不乱猜
I don't guess.
你会给我报告吧？
You'll have a report for me?
等我做完之后
When I'm finished, yes.
嗨 Ed
Hey, Ed.
我们吃了你的柠檬蛋白派
We're having lemon meringue pie.
那有两瓶胰岛素
And those two bottles of insulin.
我觉得我把你当大人看你会比较开心 对吧？
I just thought that you'd appreciate me treating you like an adult, right?
所以我直接讲了
So here's what I got.
你自己打胰岛素发生意外 过量致死
You administer your own accidental insulin overdose, and just die
但是死得还有尊严
but do it with dignity.
你睡在楼上的老婆
Your wife whose sleeping upstairs,
她还可以得到一笔昂贵的保险赔偿
she'll be the beneficiary of, what's got to be, a very generous insurance policy,
对不对？
am I right?
不过她能得到那笔钱的唯一办法 Ed
But the only way she's going to collecting that policy, Ed,
是必须让你的死是一场意外
is that we have the appearance of an accident.
如果我们动手的话 你会反抗 大叫
If we lay hands on you, you're gonna fight, squeal,
吵醒了她 我们也没办法了
she wakes up, my hands are tied.
本来只需要一个人意外死亡的 你想两人一起吗？
One accidental death is just that. Two?
而且 我也只能把这做成一场灭门惨案
No, I'll have no choice but to rock and roll a home invasion,
用无数方法虐待你老婆
violate your wife a dozen different ways,
杀了你们俩 然后烧了这房子
kill you both, burn the place to the ground.
我很抱歉 Ed Ed 嘿
I'm sorry for that. Ed, Ed, Ed, hey.
没人想虐待你老婆 好吗？
Nobody's gonna violate your wife, okay?
况且 其他人肯定会说我不是人的
Besides, what that would say about me as a human being?
生理学来讲 我不想这么做
Physiologically, it's a non-starter.
有的时候我只是喜欢乱喷 乱讲些难听的屎
Sometimes I think I just say shit, say a poop comes out of my mouth.
但我始终会拿着0.45的枪指着你
I will however plug a .45 in your brainpan.
我不怕坦白
I don't mind commitments.
可能你自己根本拿不稳枪
It's kind of sad you and your sticky fingers probably find hard to grasp.
做个决定吧 先生
Make a decision, sir.
你要去哪 先生？
Where are you going? Sir.
停下来 你们在做什么 停！
Stop that. Why're you doing that? Stop that!
喂 喂
Sir. Sir.
你们在干什么？理我一下
What are you doing? Excuse me.
Chilton先生死了
Mr. Chilton passed away.
他们让我来清理这间屋子
I was told to clean up the room.
发生了什么？
What's happening?
可以暂时出去一下吗 谢谢
Could you give us a minute, please?
这是你合约的尾款
This is the balance of your contract.
-我了解你很难受 -对 我很难受
- I understand you're upset. - Yes, I'm upset.
-但我还没有做完 -不 你做完了
- But I haven't finished yet. - Yes, you have.
Ed患糖尿病患了三十年
Ed was a diabetic for 30 years.
你觉得他会不知道自己血糖多少吗？
You think he didn't know how to check his blood sugar?
不管还有什么问题没找出来
Whatever unresolved issues remain,
我的朋友已经被人下毒杀死了
my friend was poisoned enough by them to take his own life.
所以不管他做了什么 他都被原谅了
As far as I'm concerned whatever he did is forgiven.
不好意思…我得完成 拜托
Please... I need to finish. Please.
-不好意思 我待会再来 -不 不用 进来吧
- Sorry, I'll come back. - No, no. Come in, dear.
我们谈完了
We're done.
你很厉害 Wolff先生
You're very good, Mr. Wolff.
但我希望我们未来不会再有交集了
But, I hope our paths never cross again.
我要对我最好的朋友之死负责
I'm responsible for the death of my best friend.
你会提醒我想起这件事
I'd prefer not to be reminded of it.
你觉得这是真的吗？
Do you think that's true?
Chilton真的自杀了？
That Mr. Chilton killed himself?
你觉得是我俩的责任吗？
That makes you think we're responsible?
我很难理解人们的做法
It's very hard for me to interpret what people do what they do.
这个…
This...
这个工作我还没做完 还没做完
I'm not finished. I'm not finished.
你看 看看这些
I mean look. Look at this.
SIMOPS报告 没按顺序放
SIMOPS reports. This is out of order.
他们从头重放了一次
They completely re-rearrange this.
我不能 我…
I don't. I...
我还没做完 还没做完
I'm not finished. I'm not finished.
再见 Chris
Bye, Chris.
再来一次
Again.
够了
Enough.
他们还没成
They're not done.
明天会更好 他们已经尽力了
Tomorrow is another day. They have done their best.
若是如此 你应该被打得鼻青脸肿了 而不是他们
If that were true, you would be covered in blood and snort, not them.
继续训练
Keep going.
攻击中要害能克服许多缺点
Aggression correctly channel overcomes a lot of flaws.
而要击中要害 你们自己得先脱几层皮
Tapping into that aggression requires peeling back several layers of yourself.
我的职责 是了解我儿子们的极限
It's my job to know my son's limitations.
站起来
Get up.
你们的职责 是好好蜕变
It's your job to peel.
完成你的工作 站起来
Do your job. On your feet.
没有关系 继续来吧
再来一次
Again.
我们可以直接去他家的
We could have went to his house.
在家里把他杀了 现在就该在飞机上了
Shot him in his home. We would be on a plane by now.
或者在监视器里 在他邻居的手机录像里
Or on a security camera, or some nosy neighbor's iPhone.
把那个会计叫进来
Call the bookkeeper in.
他太远了 听不到的
He's too far, he won't hear...
-现在 -我
- Now. - ... me.
我们走 起来
Let's go. Get up.
快点
Come on.
走
Move.
走吧 来吧 来
Come on, come on, come on.
Christian!
Chris!
再喊 大声点
Again. Louder.
Chris...
-不要 不 不要！ -什么鬼
- No! No! Please! - What the fuck?
Dolores!
-她得跟我来 -不要 别走 放了她
- She's coming with me. - I say, stop it! Leave her be!
见鬼！
Shit!
我们全都一起走
We're all going together.
把卡车看到后院来 快走 走
Just pull that truck around the back. Let's go. Let's go!
上车
Let's move.
走 开车！马上开！
Come on, drive! Drive now!
活见鬼了
What the fuck?
卧槽
我说到雇你的人的名字时 你就答“是”
When I say the name of your employer, you say ''Yes''.
练一次
Practice.
是
Yes.
Camorra... Juarez... Gambino...
你清楚规则的吧？
Do you understand the rules?
看我左边的口袋
My left pocket.
把你们俩都杀了 我只知道这个
Kill you both, that's all I know.
-你好啊 梦中人 -Dana有危险了
- Hello, Dreamboat. - Dana's in danger.
抹除Christian Wolff这个身份 把所有国内资金转去海外
Kill Christian Wolff. Transfer all domestic accounts overseas.
-你现在开的什么车？ -F-150
- Current vehicle? - F-150.
-你的ZZZ公司也？ -全都抹除
- Virus to triple Z? - Wipe everything.
好的 完成了 现在抹除DOT数据库里的
And... done. In the D-O-T data base now...
现在重新给你做驾照和车辆识别码
reassigning the license and vin.
有“George Boole”和“Charles Babbage”两个身份
I have “George Boole” or “Charles Babbage” in the queue.
当然是Boole
Boole. Obviously.
好吧 我应该知道的 还有什么？
Silly of me. What else?
你不该担心她
She is not your problem.
直接回到你的拖车里 开走 消失
Straight to the trailer, hook it up and disappear.
没时间了 直接去拖车吧
There's no time, only the trailer.
地址和电话 给我
Address and phone number. Get it.
她没听电话
She's not answering.
早知道我们带个小盒子了
We could use a small box.
她比照片上还小
She looked bigger in the photo.
操
God!
卧槽！贱人！
God damn! Bitch!
我们走吧
We should go.
会计怎么会那么难杀？
Since when are accountants difficult to ventilate?
死了？
Dead?
有没有搞错 他怎么杀的？用计算器砸他脑袋了？
For Chirst's, what did he do? Hit him over the head with an adding machine?
不是吧
Oh God.
好吧 那就…那就让我和客户联系
Alright, just... Put me in touch with the client.
我会自己解决这个会计
I'll handle this accountant myself.
我不能逃走 我不可能就这样一走了之！
Running isn't an option for me. I can't just walk out on my life!
我们应该去找警察 正常的纳税人都会这样做
We've to go to the police! That's what normal taxpaying people do!
警察没办法保护你 对付你的人可是还上了六亿美金
The police can't protect you from someone who could afford to return 61 million dollars.
还上了？什么意思 “还”？
Return? What are you talking about, "Return".
那些钱被人还上了
The money was being put back.
你先留在这
Stay here.
你在干什么？
What are you doing in here?
-你是谁？ -你不可以…你不该上来的
- Who are you? - You can't... You should not be here.
坐下 坐好了
Sit down. Sit right there.
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
一辆Panamerica的拖车里
Panamerica Airstream.
车长34尺7寸
34 feet 7 inches long.
宽8尺5寸
8 feet 5 inches wide.
车内空间刚好适合一个人使用 很完美
The dimensions which are perfectly adequate for one person, preferable.
你住在这里？
This is where you live?
不 我不住这
No. I don't live here.
这是一个储藏库 住这太奇怪了
This is a storage unit. That would be weird.
这是该奇怪的点吗？
That's what would be weird?
我只是在这里待得比较久
I just spend more time here.
不过 我担心有的客户会跟踪我
However, I'm afraid some of my clients have followed me.
你的客户为什么会跟踪你？你只是个会计啊
Why would your clients follow you? You're an accountant.
你怎么知道现在该做什么？为什么你在打包？
How do you know what to do here? Why are you prepared for this?
另外 这是一辆拖车
Plus, this is on wheels.
所以十二分钟内我就可以挂上车离开了 正常情况下
Which means I could hook it and be gone in 12 minutes, usually.
你在讽刺我吗？黑色幽默？
Sarcasm.Is that sarcasm?
不是 不是讽刺 我不会讽刺这个技能
No, that's not sarcasm. I don't use sarcasm material please.
我在这个世界上最重要的东西 都在拖车里了
Everything in the world that is important to me, is in this trailer.
而现在 我破例帮你 这件事危害到了一切
And right now, changing my routine for you is jeopardizing that.
那幅画不会是波洛克的真迹吧！
Tell me that's not an original Pollock.
我们该走了
We should go.
现在就走
Now.
- Medina - Medina女士
- Medina. - Ms. Medina.
我是FBI语言中心的Gordon Amundson
This is Gordon Amundson with the FBI Language Services.
啊 对 发现什么了吗？
Ah, yeah. Anything luck?
这条音轨很不寻常
It's an unusual audio file.
《所罗门·格兰迪》是十九世纪流行的一首童谣
Solomon Grundy is a nursery rhyme, circled in 1800s.
美国英语有六种音调 你这条声音里面用了四种
Your voice has four of the six intonation patterns we use to define American English.
这很难辨认出来
That's difficult to confirm with a rhyme.
不过我好奇的是 你研究的人受过心理创伤吗？
Out of curiosity...was your subject a trauma victim?
嗯？你为什么这样问？
Um. Why you ask that?
因为你在提交的档案中提到
Well, you indicated on your submission,
这个人是在高压环境里念的童谣
that this event occurred in a high-stress environment?
对 很特殊
Yeah, exceptionally.
这很有意思
That's interesting.
第一段他总过重复了四次半
The first was repeated a total of four and a half times.
音调、节奏、音量和咬字都没有任何变化
Zero variation in pitch, stem, tempo, volume or articulatory precision.
到底是什么意思？
So what does that mean exactly?
这种情况我们常常在受过心理创伤的儿童中发现
We often see this type of repetitive chanting in children who have been exposed to trauma
或者神经发育失常的人
or persons with neurodevelopmental disorders.
神经发育失常？
"Neurodevelopmental disorders?"
脆性X综合症、自闭症
Fragile-X syndrome, autism.
好吧 我告诉你 我是在查一起贼窝枪击案
Okay, so, let's say I was looking at mug shots,
这两件事有什么联系 这个人应该有什么特征？
how would that present itself, what exactly am I looking for?
脆性X的话…脸特别长 尖尖的耳朵 肌无力
Fragile-X, elongated face, protruding ears, poor muscle tone.
自闭症则很难从外表上看出来
Autism is nearly impossible to identify visually.
特征主要是在行动上 譬如难以社交和沟通
The traits are behavioral. Difficulty with social reaction and communication.
不敢和人眼神接触
Lack of eye contact.
不敢眼神接触？
好吧
Okay.
-祝你好运 -谢谢
- Good luck to you. - Thanks.
阿斯伯格综合症
Asperger's Syndrome
数学家
Mathematician
数学王子 The Prince of Mathematicians
根本不合理啊
None of this makes sense.
为什么要费那么大劲偷钱 然后又把钱放回去？
Why go to the trouble of skimming the money, if you're going to put it back?
过去三年里 Slewitt制造提交的无数张收据都被拒收了
Over the last 3 years, the number of invoices submitted by Slewitt Manufacturing had declined.
担心被抓吗？
Scared of getting caught?
价格涨了？
Price hike?
消费产品价格跌了 没有涨
The prices of consumer electronics go down not up.
对 跌了 那么…
Right. Down, yeah. Um...
我住不起这家店
I can't afford this.
我知道 我请客
I know. My treat.
全美有104人
In the U.S, 104 men, last name any standard derivation
姓氏和你那位数学家Gauss的变形一样
of your mathematician called Gauss.
而且过去七年报收超过五十万
Reported over $500,000 in any of the last 7 years.
好吧 报收下限提高一百万
Okay, go a million plus.
17人
17.
这17人里 有多少年龄在25到45之间？
Of the 17, how many between the age of 25 to 45?
4人
4.
这4个人里 只有一个人
Of those 4, only one has an income stream
他的经济来源和洗钱有关
that's cash heavy or easily laundered.
而且这个人
And he...
三年前死了
died 3 years ago.
这是什么？
What's this?
100名最有名的数学家
Names of the 100 most famous mathematicians.
好吧 我们现在知道在做什么 所以
Look, we know what we're doing now. So, just...
不如直接打他们的名字 缩小搜索范围
enter the names, narrow down the search right off the map.
我们要找白种男人 25到45岁 收入一百万以上
Male, Caucasian, 25 to 45. Earning a million plus.
没有投资收入 这人肯定只要现金
No investment income, he'll concentrate on cash.
我为什么要帮你？
What's in it for me?
嗯 你帮我找到他的话
Look, if you help me find him,
我可以努力帮你离开这里
I'll see what I can do about getting you out of here.
拜托了
Please.
单个来找还是一起来？
Single avowal or filed jointly.
嘿 你车里的那些画
Hey, those paintings in your trailer,
-都是真迹 对吧？ -对
- They're real, right? - Yes.
你不可能是在拍卖会上买的吧
You didn't buy them at auction. Did they?
是客户给我的报酬
They were a form of payment.
好吧
Right.
嘿
Hey.
谢谢你
Thank you.
在公寓里（救我）
At my apartment.
噢 是
Oh Yeah.
我们能坐一会吗？
Can we sit down for a second?
嗯 好
Yeah. Okay.
就
Just...
坐吧
have a sit.
为什么你…
How do you...?
你懂得…如何…
You know... How to...?
我父亲是一名军官 体能训练
My father was an officer, in the Army. Psychological operations.
他觉得我学这些有一天总能派上用场
He was concerned I might be taken advantage of somehow,
所以他安排了一个专家训练我 在我小的时候
so he arranged for me to train with...under a specialist, during my childhood.
我们十七年内搬了34次家
We live in 34 homes in 17 years.
-搬了34次？-嗯
- You moved 34 times? - Mm.
天啊 你们真牛
God, that's extraordinary.
现在我知道你童年有多惨了
Now I'm sure it must have been difficult.
我从没去过别的地方
I've never been anywhere.
只去过坎昆市 一点都不骄傲
Only Cancun,not my proudest moment.
嗯
Um.
我的意思是…
I just mean...
你的人生…很独特
Your life is... unique.
并不独特 我患有
It's not unique, I have...
高强度的自闭症
high functioning form of autism Which...
我的视角特别狭窄
means I have an extremely narrow focus,
而且一旦接受任务就一定要把它完成
and a hard time abandoning tasks once I've taken them up.
和不认识的人社交我也有困难
I have difficulties socializing with other people I don't know,
我想社交的
but I want to.
在我高中毕业那年
When I was a senior in high school.
我想准备一条特别的裙子去参加毕业舞会
I wanted this special dress for prom.
我告诉自己 花一百块去买条垃圾裙子
I told myself that spending a hundred bucks on a trashy dress
我一生也就只会穿一次 就是去参加舞会
that I was going to wear one time to an event
而且那裙子我还不喜欢
that I thought was silly in the first place,
-根本就是… -浪费
- it's just... - Wasteful.
对
Yes.
然后Vera Wang有一条经典的露肩小黑裙
But Vera Wang made this black strapless classic,
那裙子贵非常多 但你可以穿着它去参加很多活动
it was more expensive but you could wear it to all kinds of future events.
-这就是投资 -对！
- It's an investment. - Yes!
你在哪上高中的？
Where were you when I was in high school?
以色列
Oh, North Carolina. Israel.
好吧 嗯
Right. Um.
问题就是 那条裙子要价1700美元
The problem is. They wanted $1700 dollars for this dress,
我根本买不起 所以我…
and I didn't have that so...
-你向父母要钱？ -没有
- You asked your parents? - No.
慢慢听
Hang on.
二十一点 我从来没玩过这个
Black Jack. I never played a hand but I...
我去图书馆 看了所有讲二十一点攻略的书
went to the library and checked out all these books on strategy.
然后我通过数学俱乐部去了小赌城！
And I turned the Naperville North math club into a little Vegas!
-什么是“数学俱乐部”？-就是数学俱乐部
- What's a "math club"? - Math club.
就是和其他学校比赛
You compete against other schools.
比数学理论和算数速度
Theory and speed math.
比如298567乘92等于多少
Like what's 298,567 times 92.
27,468,164.
对 嗯
Right. Um.
讲回二十一点
Black Jack.
我懂得了怎么打 怎么分
I could tell you when to hit, stand, split, re-split,
怎么去算牌 随机猜牌 还有扣牌
then moved on to card counting, shuffle tracking, hole carding.
然后我拿着我全部身家183美元
And I took everything I had, which is $183 dollars,
开车去了Harrahs赌场
and I drove down to Harrahs in Joliet.
-为什么那条裙子那么重要？-不是裙子的问题
- Why was this dress so important to you? - It wasn't about the dress.
而是我希望我穿着它走进舞会时 大家都会“哇”
I just wanted to walk into that gym and have everybody say “Wow.”
我只是想…
I was trying to...
慢慢听 我想融入大家
Hold on.I was trying to connect.
可能不管我俩有多不一样 但我们都想做同一件事
I think no matter how different, we're all trying to do the same thing.
后来 玩的前十分钟我就输了二十块
But I... I lost all but 20 bucks in the first 10 minutes.
然后我把剩下的钱都放进了硬币机里 赢了两千！
Fed that into a nickel slot on the way out and I won 2 grand.
买裙子剩下的钱我用来租了辆林肯
I used the extra cash to pay for a limo.
但其实那条裙子我也就穿了一次
Only wore the dress just the one time.
Chris 为什么我们来这家酒店？
Chris, why are we here?
嗯…
Um...
我觉得这家酒店水压很舒服
I thought this hotel had good water pressure.
奥罗拉的假日快捷酒店水压也很舒服啊
The Holiday Inn Express in Aurora has good water pressure.
对 但这家的毛巾也很棒
Yes, but these towels are very fancy.
便宜的酒店毛巾很差
Cheaper hotels have scratchy towels.
而且…
And...
我希望你喜欢这里
I wanted you to like it.
Crazy Eddie和Panama Pump公司
Crazy Eddie and the Panama Pump.
Crazy Eddie和Panama Pump公司 你听说过他们吗？
Crazy Eddie Antar and the Panama Pump. Have you ever heard of it?
什么？
What?
Crazy Eddie Antar这人
Crazy Eddie Antar! He owned a...
在八十年代纽约开了电子产品的连锁店
a string of electronics stores on New York City in the '80s.
而这个人 基本上刚开店就开始偷钱
Crazy Eddie Antar, he started stealing almost as soon as he opened his business.
好 我终于听懂了
Okay, I'm not following.
他把钱存在以色列 然后再取出来
He deposited money in Tel Aviv, then he cycled them
通过Panama Pump公司 投资回他的商店
through Panama and bring back into his stores.
好吧 为什么呢？为什么要拿出来又投回来？
Okay, why? Why take it out and put it back?
一开始他偷钱只是为了普通的避税
Well, initially he was just stealing and garden-variety taxes evasion.
但后来他想出了更好的主意
But he came up with a better idea.
你看 用他自己的钱
You see, by taking his own money,
在账本上进进出出
stealing it and putting it back on his books.
就成了流动资金
It was raining cash.
他的公司上市时每股只要八美元
He took the company public at eight dollars a share.
一年后暴涨至七十五美元
A year later it was trading at seventy-five.
Rita也在给Living Robotics搞上市
Rita's taking Living Robotics public.
对
Yes.
可是如果这样为什么她还要请你？
But why would she hire you in the first place if she thought you'd figure it out?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我们得去问问她
I'll have to ask her.
不管Rita怎么打算的 都不该是你关心的事
Whatever Rita's involve in, it's not your concern.
你尽管消失 我来打电话
You disappear, I make a call.
拜托了 我很担心你
Please. I'm worried about you.
如果我不反击的话 Dana会死的
If I don't do something, Dana will die.
你为了一个认识只有一周的女孩冒生命危险？
Risking your life for a girl you known a week.
为什么？
Why?
一声叹息 你怎么打算的？
Heavy sigh. What's the plan?
找出想杀她的人
Find the person who wants to kill her.
然后呢？
And?
打爆他的头
Shoot him in the head.
最后一个了
Last one.
一头姓“狼”的 名Christian
Wolff, two "FF"s. Christian.
有245人叫这个
245 men.
四人收入超过百万
Four with incomes over a million.
但是全都年过六十 抱歉
All over the age of sixty. Sorry.
不过 你们找的是“会计”
But...your guy's an accountant.
有两个叫Christian Wolff的有会计资格证
Two Christian Wolffs own CPA first .
第一个Christian Wolff经营了Wolff会计所
The first Christian Wolff, owns Wolff Accounting,
在亚利桑那州Scottsdale的南街121号
121 South Street, Scottsdale, Arizona.
去年收入43万5千 生意不错
Income of 435 grand. It's a good year.
赚得多以至于我们两年前还查过他
So good, we audited him 2 years ago.
他很清白
He's clean.
另一位Christian Wolff
The other Christian Wolff.
也不对
Nope.
收入只有7万5
Only 75 grand.
ZZZ会计所
ZZZ Accounting.
伊州平原镇的沃巴什路上
Wabash Way, Plainfield, Illinois.
取名ZZZ 在黄页上根本找不到
ZZZ, it's not exactly a smart Yellow pages move.
等一等
Wait a second.
谁帮沃巴什路上的阿金美甲店报税？
Who filed the returns for Kim's nails, Wabash Way, Plainfield
ZZZ会计所
ZZZ Accounting.
-可能因为是邻居… -那家中餐馆呢
- Could just be the neighbor... - Great Mandarin, Wabash.
ZZZ会计所
ZZZ Accounting.
保罗洗衣店呢？
Paul's Laundromat.
-ZZZ会计所 -ZZZ会计所
- ZZZ Accounting. - ZZZ Accounting.
他们不会全都登记的合作关系吧？
Tell me they are all registered as partnerships.
全都是
Everyone.
经营合伙人Christian Wolff
Managing partner: Christian Wolff.
- 他叫Christian Wolff -什么？
- Christian Wolff. - What?
Christian Wolff 这个人去年通过会计公司赚了75543美元
Christian Wolff, last year ran $75,543 through his accounting firm...
等等 谁是Christian Wolff？
Whoa. Who is Christian Wolff?
那个会计
The accountant.
噢？
Well...
-7万5 那开价还蛮低的 -我同意 但是…
- 75 grand, that's chump change. - Agreed, but...
他通过阿金美甲店赚了28万7765
He ran another $287,765 through Kim's Nails,
大华中餐馆赚了44万5112 还有更重要的
$445,112 trough Great Mandarin Chinese, and you'll love this...
保罗洗衣店赚了50万5909！
$505,909 through Paul's Laundromat.
一家洗衣店？怎么可能！？
Paul's Laundromat?! Are you fucking kidding me?
他在耍我们呢
He's playing with us.
他没办法通过一家会计公司把钱洗干净
He can't clean that kind of money through an accounting firm.
会留下太多痕迹
The paper trail's too heavy.
所以他通过现金交易的商店来洗钱
So he's laundering it through cash businesses.
全都在芝加哥南边的一个小商场外完成
All of those were in the same strip mall south of Chicago.
ZZZ？
ZZZ?
他才不管叫什么名字呢 只是一个名字
I mean, he doesn't care about the traffic, it's a front,
什么Christian Wolff、Carl Gauss、Lou ‘Lewis' Carroll 都是代号
All of it. “Christian Wolff,” "Carl Gauss", “Lou ‘Lewis' Carroll.”
他喜欢用这些有名的数学家名字来做化名
He's using the names of famous mathematicians as a cover.
去年他给Harbor神经研究所捐了善款
Charitable Contributions here to Harbor Neuroscience last year alone,
-捐了差不多有… -110万美元
- that's got to come to close to... -  One million one hundred dollars.
这不是掩护 这件事是真的 我查过了
That one's not a cover. That's the real deal, I've checked.
所以这个人冒着生命危险去做会计
So you're telling me this guy risks his life doing forensic accounting
为世界上最危险的人工作
for some of the scariest people on the planet,
还花那么多工夫去洗钱
collect his fee, goes to all the trouble laundering it
结果却几乎把所有的钱都捐掉了？
and then gives almost all of it away.
可能他还收其他的报酬呢？
What if he's taking other means of payment?
对 有可能
Yeah. Possible, yeah.
我抓到他了 Ray
I caught him, Ray.
可能是吧
Maybe.
回去收拾一下 我们得去芝加哥
Pack your bag. We're going to Chicago.
有90%的可能他们都是右撇子
90% probability they are all right-handed.
他们欺负我只是意外
It was an accident.
对我而言只是站起来打一架
To me it's stand forth, right wrist.
可能你喜欢在学校后面等着被打吧
Thought maybe you enjoy waiting in the schoolyard sucker punch.
生命充满了一系列选择 没什么新鲜的
Life is a series of choices, none of which are new.
最老的选择是选择要做个受害者
The oldest is choosing to be a victim
还是不要
or choose not to.
第二个选择 关于忠诚
Second oldest, loyalty.
永远把家人放在第一位 不管好时坏时
Family first, good times or bad.
你们好啊 小兔崽子
Bonjour, fellows.
我戴的新眼镜
They are new glasses.
你觉得你不打回去的话 他们就会喜欢你？
You think if... you don't fight back, then maybe they'll like you?
他们就不再挑剔你和嘲笑你是怪胎？
Stop picking on you, calling you freak?
真相是
Here's what it is.
他们不喜欢你 他们也不是讨厌你
They don't like you, they don't dislike you.
他们怕你 因为你和他们不一样
They are afraid of you. You're different.
不一样迟早都会吓到别人
Sooner or later different scares people.
要做个受害者吗？做出你的选择吧
Victim or not? Make your decision.
上
Go.
你不一样
You're different.
不一样迟早都会吓到别人
Sooner or later different scares people.
里面来
In here.
0.357口径的枪
.357 Colt Python.
序列号已经被弄走了
Serial number's gone.
Hydra-Shok
无线安全摄像头
Wireless security cam.
红外线 防水
Infrared, weatherproof.
他有一整套装备
He's got a network of them.
整个后院都有他的监控
The whole backyard he's got eyes.
就是这个人了
This is our guy.
这个危险的人为什么住在这里？
So why is a guy who's up to his elbows in cash live here?
从他的客户群来看 他觉得融入社会可以活得更久吧
Given his clientele, he figures blending in will extend his shelf life.
挺聪明的
It's the smart move.
可能还不够聪明
Well, maybe not smart enough.
我把这里的监视器都拆了
I take security cameras back here.
那么任何人都可以从前门攻进来
Anybody can roll up from the front.
他要怎么防护？
How does he cover this?
我的上帝老天爷啊！
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
这个可不常见
Don't see that everyday.
孩子们 我们来做个情况报告吧
Boys, let's have a situation report.
Ike 好吗？
Are we good, Ike?
一切安全
All clear.
太好了
Rock and roll.
Sport你呢？
And how about you, sport?
我叫Bobby
It's Bobby.
我这也没有情况
I got nothing.
需要这么劳师动众吗？
Is all this really necessary?
你应该监视下他的家
You should be watching his home.
是吗 你这样想啊 那是你的想法
Yeah. That what you think? That your idea of a subject.
我喜欢别人告诉我怎么工作
I love it when people tell me how to do my job.
我相信我更推荐让你离开美国
I believe I recommended you to leave the country.
-你拒绝了 -他是个会计啊！
- You declined. - He's an accountant!
从他的眼中
I could see it in his eyes.
我知道他不可能让我跑掉的
The freak wasn't going to let it go.
-帮我向Michelle问好 -我会的
- Give my best to Michelle. - I will.
十年前我就老了
I was old 10 years ago.
你有什么故事 Medina？
So what's your story, Medina?
你知道的
You know my story.
我只知道法院说的版本
I know what the Court said.
我把一包可卡因塞到了毒贩的鼻子里
I stuffed a handful of cocaine up a drug dealer's nose.
然后在他的车里用枪柄打他
Pistol-whipped him in the trunk of his car.
那时我才十七岁 那件事发生在八月
I was seventeen. It was August.
他昏迷了三天 但还是活下来了
He coked for three days, but lived.
你后悔吗？
Do you regret it?
给他塞的药是硼砂
The coke was half borax.
就是他卖给我姐姐的垃圾
Same shit he kept selling me sister.
现在她在Annapolis当了牙医
She's a dental hygienist in Annapolis now.
结婚了 有三个孩子
Married with 3 kids.
所以 我不后悔
And, I don't regret it.
很不容易
That's rough.
不好意思 King主任
All due respect, Director King,
你又了解Wolff多少呢？
what the fuck do youknow about Wolff?
-等等 我要打电话叫人！-退后！
-Wait, I gonna call them in! -Move back!
不如你告诉我 Medina?
What don't you tell me, Medina?
男人会因为很多原因杀害彼此
Men kill each other for any number of reasons.
钱财 权力 恐惧
Money, power, fear.
去死吧，混蛋！
Take that, motherfucker!
那天在Ravenite死了九个人
9 men had died that day at the Ravenite.
但都不是因为这些原因
But for none of those reasons.
是那些人从会计身上夺走了东西
They had taken something from the man who was killing them.
一种不可挽回的东西
Something that couldn't be made whole again.
对他而言非常重要的东西
Something very important to him.
所以他有血有肉地去了那里
And he was there for his pound of flesh.
拜托
Please.
请停手吧！
Just fucking stop it!
把枪放下
Put your gun down!
“小托尼”Bazzano
"Little Tony" Bazzano.
我在货车里窃听他了六个月
I'd been wasting in a van for 6 months
听着这个傲慢的混蛋吹牛打屁
listening to that arrogant little prick belch, fart, and brag.
那天他的声音里全是恐惧 我甚至没听出来
I didn't recognize his voice with all the fear in it.
我没有动过他 我没动过那个老头
I didn't touch him. I didn't touch that old man.
我根本……
I wasn't even...
会计是回来复仇的
Our man had come for revenge
他成功了
and he got it.
杀了九个人
Nine dead.
我本来该是第十个
And I was tenth.
你叫什么？
Your name?
Ray.
Raymond King.
谁雇你来这 Raymond King？
Who employs you, Raymond King?
我是财政部的员工
I'm a Treasury Agent.
你是好人吗？
Are you a good one?
不 不是 不能算好人
No. No. Not particularly.
就这样吗？
Is that it?
孩子 我…我是一个父亲！
Kids. I got...I'm a dad.
我有两个孩子
I got 2 kids.
成年了吗？
Grown?
嗯
Yeah.
对 他们…他们都成年了
Yes. Yes. They're all... They're all grown up.
你是个好父亲吗 Rayond King?
Were you a good dad, Rayond King?
是 我一直是个好父亲
Yeah. I've been a good dad.
我是个坏员工 我也很懦弱
I'm a lousy agent and I've been a weak man,
但是父亲 我当得非常好
but that...that I didn't screw up.
我是个好父亲
That I got right.
我本来只是个财政部的员工
Imagine you were a Treasury agent approaching the twilight of a
就要结束自己碌碌无为的工作生涯…
spectacularly dismal career...
突然有一天
And then one day...
却找到了一丝曙光
that break you should've been looking for...
找到了Francis Silveberg 一个洗黑钱界的传奇人物
Francis Silveberg, the black money legend,
他在哈瓦那、拉斯维加斯和蒙特卡洛都赫赫有名
who cleaned cash from Monte Carlo to Havana to Vegas.
他帮甘比诺一家保管账簿超过四十年
He kept the books for the Gambino family for forty plus years.
直到一天 甘比诺的老大——“大托尼”Bazzano
Until one day, the boss, "Big Tony" Bazzano,
觉得Francis上了年纪 未来若是问询起来会对自己很不利
thought maybe the old man's age made him vulnerable to prosecution.
就让他的儿子“小托尼”去杀了Francis
Ordered his son, "Little Tony", to kill Francis.
孩子人没杀成
Kid fucked it up.
反倒让Francis跑到了警察局 成为证人以换得政府的保护
Francis ran, became a was a federal informant in return for protective custody.
这件事本可以改变我的工作
It could've turned my career around
但是我没有听他所讲
only If I had listened.
我没有
I didn't.
他又被赶了出去
He was processed out.
然后他失去了唯一的保护伞
And he lost the only protection he had.
大门开启
Please stand clear of the gate.
而在他作证指控“大托尼”时我们承诺过要保护他
The protection that he was promised when he testified against "Big Tony".
这一次出去 “小托尼”赶紧动手
And this time, "Little Tony" got it right.
几个小时就抓到了他
He had Francis in a couple of hours.
他们在布朗克斯的地下室里把他捆住
down in a filthy basement in the Bronx, nailed to a chair,
折磨致死
tortured to death.
所以我…资源加入了这个共同行动小组
So I...volunteered for a joint task force,
坐在Ravenite的货车里监视了几个月
Sat outside the Ravenite surveillance van for months
希望能找到些证据指控杀Francis的人
hoping to get a shred of evidence to use against Francis's killers.
等等 我要打电话叫人！
Wait, I gonna call them in!
退后！
Move back!
我希望我能在那弥补我的罪过
I went in there hoping I could ease my guilt.
然后我遇上了这位会计刺客
And I met our accountant.
他为什么放过我 我不知道
Why he let me live, I didn't know .
但他改变了我的一生
But he changed my life.
我向财政局递交了辞呈
I gave my notice to the department.
开始再一次对每一天充满期待
I started looking forward to the day again.
感受阳光在我脸上
You know, feeling the sun on my face.
也戒了酒
Quit drinking.
那天我正要离开
I was on my way out the door...
忽然电话响了
and then the phone rang.
Ray King.
我永远不会忘记那声音
I'll never forget that voice.
你喜欢猜谜吗 Raymond King?
Do you like puzzles, Raymond King?
她告诉我她为会计刺客工作
She tells me she works for the accountant.
还告诉我一艘包着中国国旗的金属船
And that a shipping container packed with Chinese nationals
正在驶向纽约港
is passing through the Port of New York.
几个月后
A few months later,
一吨Wario Cartel的水货运到了迈阿密
one ton of uncut Wario Cartel product is entering Miami.
你把这些事情都联系在了一起
All those cases you put together.
雾里看花
Smoke and mirrors.
他到底是谁…
So, who is he...
这个会计杀手
this “accountant”?
Leavenworth监狱最高级别狱室的编号831
Prisoner 831, Fort Leavenworth maximum security.
军方监狱？
Military prison?
他是个军人
So he was in the army.
军队背景让他可以联系到基地组织的洗钱手
Army let him to us to track Al-Qaeda money launderers
他从Leavenworth被换到哥伦比亚特区的青少年拘留所
He was transferred from Leavenworth to our detention center in DC.
做五个人做的重活
Did the work of five men.
挖掘数据 分析表格
Data Mining, Basket Analysis.
他和Francis住一间房
He roomed with Francis.
他们有自己的世界 一起下棋 一起吃饭
They kept to themselves. Played chess. Ate together.
一起看电视
Sat in a TV room together.
形影不离
They were inseparable.
后来一天 等一名警卫告诉Wolff
And then one day, a guard told Wolff why Francis
Francis出狱后从不给他电话或写信的原因
hadn't called or written since he got out.
以及Francis的尸体在填充场被发现后
And his burned body had been found on a Staten Island landfill.
Wolff咆哮着狂追这名警卫
Wolff snapped, went after the guard.
用一个膳魔师杯子打裂了那警卫的头盖骨
He fractured the man's skull with a thermos.
然后从三楼窗户跳下来逃走了
Escaped from a third-floor window.
带走了杯子
Took the thermos.
他就做了这些吗？
That's all you got?
-Leavenworth可是有军方的人在啊 -记录有很多都是杜撰的
- I mean, Leavenworth, they would have military...- Records are all heavily redacted.
那还有逮捕记录啊这些东西
Well then, arrest records, something.
03年春天 伊州坎卡基一个葬礼上
Spring of 2003, at a funeral home in Kankakee, Illinois.
年轻的会计把6名当地人送进了医院
Our boy sent 6 locals to the hospital with a variety of injuries.
他们中没人认识他
No one knew Wolff.
和Wolff一起去葬礼的男人后来被认出是一名美军上校
The older man who came with him was identified as a colonel, US Army.
殡仪馆
Funeral home.
谁的葬礼？
Whose wake?
那天只有一个顾客
One customer that day.
Lauren Alton女士
Mrs. Lauren Alton.
她在坎卡基教一年级学生教了13年
Mrs. Alton taught first grade for 13 years in Kankakee.
死时有一名丈夫、两个12岁和10岁的儿子
Survived by a husband and two boys, ages 12 and 10.
所有记录都显示她是个平凡人
By all accounts, an ordinary life, well-lived
只是英年早逝而已
but cut short.
不好意思 先生 这里只能亲属进入
Excuse me, sir. This is family only.
先生 请你过来 我必须请你出去
Sir, please come over. I'll have to ask you to step outside.
然后就打了起来 闹得很大
And then a fight breaks out. A brawl really.
现场人员也控制不住
Over what, the authorities never...get down.
拿开你的脏手
Get your hands off me.
警察来了
Deputies respond.
会计恼怒的时候警察们严阵以待 拔出了枪
A barney fife type squares off with our boy gets rattled, pulls his gun.
上校竞直为他挡了那些枪子
The colonel just stepped in front of the 83 weapon.
军队收押了两人
Army collected both men.
警方报告里写Wolff是“士兵一号”
Police report named Wolff as "Soldier one".
去世女人的丈夫后来通过名字认出来
The widower identified the colonel by name.
上校是他前妻的前夫
His late wife's former husband.
我查过了 那是个假名
I've checked, it's an alias.
不比Christian Wolff真多少
No more real than "Christian Wolff."
死去的女人是上校的前妻
She was the dead colonel's ex-wife.
你觉得上校是Wolff的谁呢?
And you think Wolff is what to him?
你是个好父亲吗？Ray King?
Were you a good dad? Ray King?
我想在接电话之前弄清楚
I've given up trying to figure out when I'll get a call.
为什么找我 给我打电话
The why though, that I got.
有人打破了自己的道德界限
Someone breaks his moral code.
你为什么和我说这些？
Why are you telling me this?
还有几个月我就要退休了
I'm retiring in a few months.
她再打电话来
When she calls...
总得有人接她的电话
somebody needs to be there to answer.
不行
No.
他是个罪犯 Ray
He's a criminal, Ray.
对
Yeah.
他帮助毒贩、洗黑钱的
He aids and abets drug cartels, money launderers.
妈的他还是个杀手！
He's a fucking killer.
相信我 我也曾这样挣扎过
Believe me, I've wrestled with the same decision.
但当我接到第一通电话时
But when I got that first call,
我意识到了
I realized something.
我花了一辈子的时间才意识到这些幸运的时刻
I spent my whole life only recognizing my lucky breaks after they were gone.
那个女人 她是谁？
The Brit, who is she?
喂？
Hello?
Medina小姐
Miss. Medina
让这位官员把脚从家具上拿下来
tell Eliot Ness to get his feet off the furniture.
这里不是农场
He's not in a barn.
Living Robotics 记下来
Living Robotics. Write it down.
身高六尺多 短发 体格健壮 是吧？
More than 6 feet, short hair, athletic build, yes?
对
Correct.
你说的那种短发 和我的短发一样？
When you say short hair, you mean short hair like my hair?
-还是说这一种短发？ -什么…有什么不一样？
- Or you mean short hair like short hair? - You... What's the difference?
你说你可以解决问题 就解决吧！
I was told you could fix this, so fix it!
但你和这个人说过话 对吧？你和他说过话
But you did speak to the man, am I right? You spoke to him.
他声音什么样？
What did he sound like?
我们简单聊过 他声音怎么样有什么关系
We made small talk, what's it matter what he sounds like?
是Ike是吧？北面传来的？
That's Ike, right? Is it north side?
嘿Bobby 是你吗？
Yo Bobby, was that you?
Bob.
Bobby.
Ike 你还在吗？
Ike, are you there?
Ike?
别到处乱跑了 答复我啊 Ike？
Guys, stop fucking around, someone answer me. Ike?
从左攻入
Course to the left.
你可能得用高级的弹道分析数据
You might consider using a round with superior ballistic coefficient.
给我这间房子的平面图
Give me the layout of the home.
入口 走廊 房间 掩护物
Points of entry, corridors, rooms, cover.
上
Go.
卧槽！
Fuck!
坐下
Sit down.
-发生了什…？ -闭嘴 坐在椅子上
- What's this all...? - Shut up and sit down in the chair.
你见过一颗子弹可以每秒穿梭3000英尺
You ever see a magic green round traveling 3000 feet per second
还射穿这扇窗户吗？
go through a window?
没人见过
Nobody does.
趴下 赶紧
Get down, now!
你们四个 去前门入口
4 men, front entrance.
直接上 快去
Go right at him, go now.
你
You,
我来监控 你和他们一起
I got the cameras. Go join your friends.
起来！
Up!
安全
Clear.
烟雾弹
Smoke.
走！走！
Move! Move!
上
Go! Go!
上！
Go!
有人死了
Man down!
我在前门入口
I'm at the front entrance,
都被杀了！
pinned down!
都死了吗？
Are they dead?
我需要情况报告 死了几个了？
I need situation info. How many down?
他们都死了吗？回答我！
Are they dead? Answer me!
好吧 他在房顶了 跟着我 我们走
Okay, he's on the roof. Now, follow me, let's move.
检查房顶 检查窗户
Check the skylight. Check the window.
这个混蛋进来的时候 我想听到枪响
When that motherfucker comes in, I want to hear gun shots,
还有“目标清楚”
and I want to hear "Target eliminated".
够了 他妈的他已经在房子里了！
That's enough. He's in the god damn house!
出去解决这一切！
Get out there and end this!
Brax 给我情况报告 你看见什么了吗？
Brax, give me a situation report. Have you got eyes on anything?
到底发生了什么？
What's happening?
说话啊！
Say something!
所罗门·格兰迪 星期一落地
Solomon Grundy, born on a Monday,
星期二受洗
Christened on Tuesday,
星期三结婚
Married on Wednesday
星期四染疾
Took ill on Thursday,
星期五病重
Grew worse on Friday,
星期六去世
Died on Saturday,
星期天入土
Buried on Sunday,
这就是所罗门·格兰迪的一生
That was the end, Of Solomon Grundy.
这是什么鬼！
WHAT IS THIS?
嘿 嘿 趴下
Hey! Hey! Stand down!
去死吧！
Fuck off!
你好 Braxton
Hello, Braxton.
不要
Don't...
别这样
Don't do that.
我找你找了十年了 你要这样出现在我面前
I've been looking for you for 10 years, and you're going to come at me like
我们昨天还见过面呢 你就这样对我吗？
we just saw each other yesterday.That's what you got to do?
但这个情况 嗯 我觉得…
But...this. Well, I think...
我还以为你看见我会很开心呢 我以为
Well, I think that you're going to be happy to see me, I guess.
我很高兴
I am happy.
我需要做完它
I need to finish.
你应该离开
You should go.
我该走？
I should go?
好啊 我 我会走
Okay, I...Okay, I'll just go.
但首先我要问你件事情
But first I'm gonna ask you a question.
你得给我个答案
You're going to give me an answer.
你和爸爸为什么要去那个葬礼！？
Why would you and Pop go to that funeral?
她抛弃了我们 你不记得了吗？你难道不记得了吗？
She left us, did you not remember that? Did you not remember that!
因为你爸爸才死的 你知道吗？
It's your fault that Pop's dead, you hear me?
-因为你！ -对不起 Braxton
- It's your fault! - I'm sorry, Braxton.
对不起？对不起能干什么 你个怪胎！
You're sorry? Sorry doesn't cut it, you weird fuck!
操
Shit.
你根本不关心我 你根本不在乎我
You don't give a shit about me. You don't give a shit about me.
现在还不在乎吗？
How about now?
你想打架吗？
Are you going to fight?
来啊
Fight!
我很抱歉 Braxton
I'm sorry, Braxton.
你懂吗 如果你要去看她
You know, If you had to see her...
如果你一定要去看她
If that was something that you had to do.
你得找我去！
You call me.
我是你弟弟！
I'm your brother.
我永远都会支持你
I always have your back.
你不能找爸爸 你该找我
You don't call him, you call me.
你从来没想到我在哪吗？
Did you even wonder where I was?
我知道你在哪
I know where you were.
我只希望你安全
I just wanted you to be safe.
我的一些客户
Some of my clients are...
他们很危险
quite dangerous.
我这个人也同样危险
I kind of consider fairly dangerous myself.
对 你变厉害了
Well, you've made an improvement.
去死你
Shit, man.
我们俩在这儿碰见
You and me here,
-真是… -对 从统计学上来讲
- Yeah, it's... - Well, statistically speaking...
天啊 我在夸张呢
Christ, man! It's rhetorical.
你当真了？
I mean, really?
太荒谬了
It was just insane.
不开心
Not happy.
你考虑过什么是重要的吗 Wolff先生？
Do you consider what you do important, Mr. Wolff?
除了你自己之外
To someone other than yourself, I mean.
我做的就很重要！
What I do is.
Living Robotics为人们提供无价的帮助
Living Robotics public offering would have been worth billions.
投钱去研究神经学、纳米技术
Money to be used for neuroprosthetics, nanotechnology.
你呢？
You?
天晓得我为什么要请你？
Why in god's name did I ever hire you?
请我帮你整理账簿
To leak-proof your books.
Dana发现了问题 你想确认这个问题公布出去也不是问题
Dana found a mistake, and you wanted to be sure it's safe to go public.
现在你想杀了她
And now you want to kill her.
我很喜欢Dana
I'm fond of Dana.
但我是帮助众人的 不是Dana！是帮我！
But I restore lives, not Dana! ME!
帮男人女人和小孩 我给他们希望
Men, women, children. I give them hope.
让他们变得健全
Make them whole.
你懂这些东西吗？
Do you even know what that's like?
我当然懂
Yes, I do.
对不起
Sorry.
我很想你
I missed you.
我也很想你 Braxton
I missed you too, Braxton.
我很想你 因为我爱你
I missed you too because I love you.
你是我哥哥
You're my brother.
可能
Maybe...
你想…
Would you want to...
可能一周内我还能见到你？
Maybe I can see you in a week?
讲个地方 我会去的
Name the place, I'll be there.
我怎么找你？
How will I find you?
你不用找我
You won't.
我来找你
I'll find you.
Helen.
你怎么回应有流言说那些受害人
How do you responds to rumors that some of the victims had wounds
身上有防空武器造成的伤口？
consistent with anti-aircraft rounds?
我只能说芝加哥警察很有经验
I'd say the Chicago police department has ample experience
解决各种谋杀情况
solving all manner of homicides.
先生 那和Lamar Blackburn先生和他姐姐Rita的死
Sir, how are the conspiracy and fraud charges related to
相关的阴谋论你又怎么解释呢？
the deaths of Lamar Blackburn and his sister, Rita?
这个情况很复杂
This is a very fluid situation.
过去48小时我们发现了很多新情况
With a lot of surprising revelations over the last 48 hours.
让我介绍我们这个调查小组的组长来解答吧
Let me introduce you to the person leading the investigation.
Medina调查员
Agent Medina.
下午好
Good afternoon.
不管我有多想揽这个功劳
As much as I like to take credit for this,
我都不能这样做
I can't.
因为这是团队协作的成果
Because this was... a team effort,
靠大家长时间的传统调查工作
comprised of long hours of good old-fashioned investigative work.
还有问题吗？
Questions?
我们可以知道…
Can we get more information...
新罕布什尔州 Harbor精神研究所
Harbor Neuroscience Hanover, New Hampshire
他曾经和其他两个孩子一样 曾经也很快乐
He was just like our other two, he was a happy baby.
但现在他很少说话 感觉就像 这个孩子在消失
Now, he rarely speaks. It's like, our child is missing.
他不在了 他迷失了 需要我们的帮助
He's not there. He's lost and he needs our help.
我们觉得…
We thought...
我们觉得…我们希望他还能回到从前那样
We thought...we hoped that he'd catch back up,
但他没有
but he didn't.
美国有68分之一的孩子被诊断出患有自闭症
1 in 68 children in this country are diagnosed with a form of autism.
但是如果有那么一刻 你愿意抛下预期
But if you can put aside for a moment what your pediatrician
和其他NT对你儿子的评价
and all the other NT's have said about your son...
NT？
“NT's”?
拥有典型神经系统的人 就好像我们
“Neuro-typicals.”  The rest of us.
如果我们错了呢？
What if we're wrong?
是我们用了错的测试标准来衡量自闭症的儿童？
What if we've been using the wrong tests to quantify intelligence in children with autism?
你儿子并不差
Your son's not less-than.
他只是不一样
He's different.
从现在开始 你对他的期望将会逐渐改变
Now, your expectations for your son may change over time,
他们可能会结婚 生小孩 自给自足
they might include marriage, children, self-sufficiency.
也有可能不会
They might not.
但我向你保证
But I guarantee you.
如果我们让世界给孩子们定了标准
If we let the world set expectations for our children,
他们的起点就永远是低的
they'll start low
而且止步不前
and they'll stay there.
可能你的儿子能做的事超乎你所想
Maybe your son is capable of much more than you know.
也有可能…有可能
And maybe... Just maybe...
他只是不懂怎么和我们说
He doesn't understand how to tell us.
或者
Or...
我们没有学会怎么去听
we haven't yet learned how to listen.
嘿 宝贝 我讲了几百次了 别这样到处乱逛
Hey, honey, for the hundredth time, don't wonder off like that.
-很抱歉 -没关系 没有关系
- I'm so sorry. - It's alright. It's fine.
他可以和你待一会吗 Justine？
Can he visit with you for a while, Justine?
好的
Okay, good.
-来吧 我来带你们参观一下 -你还好吗？
- C'mon, folks, I'll give you the nickel tour. - You okay with that?
没问题的 来吧
It's okay. Come on.
哎 他没事的
Oh, he'll be fine.
Justine是我们几个长期住户之一
Justine's one of our few full-time residents.
她三十年前开始就不讲话了
She stopped talking 30 years ago,
现在靠电子翻译器来交流
communicates with a digital translator now.
博士 这个研究所哪来的资金运作？
Doctor, how is Harbor funded?
我们很幸运 有大方的私人捐款
We are fortunate to have very generous private donors.
-他们真的很大方 -为什么这么说？
- I'll say they're generous. - Why is that?
-刚刚那个女人 Justine -我的女儿
- That woman, Justine. - My daughter.
她是你女儿？
She's your daughter?
因为她我开了这个机构
The reason I started the Institute.
她的电脑是一台BX-32 自动冷却 12核心
Justine's computer, it's a BX-32. Water-cool, 12 Core.
对啊 你是个软件工程师
That's right, you're a software engineer.
这个嘛 有的捐助人是比较大方
Well, some of our donors are more generous than others.
怎么了？那台电脑很好用吗？
Why? Is that a good computer?
好用？
Good?
博士 她可以用那台电脑黑掉五角大楼
Doc, she could backdoor the Pentagon with that rig.
嗨 梦中人 可以聊天吗？
Hello, Dreamboat. Shall we chat?
-嗨 -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
在这里签字 谢谢
Sign here, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
-谢谢你 -不客气
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
（这是女主提过的《狗狗打扑克》那幅画）
中文字幕翻译 by Ravine YANG 杨小溪：）
Subtitle created by - Aorion -